<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick wordclouds from PubMed abstracts - using PMID lists in R</title>
      <link>/2016/09/quick-wordclouds-pubmed-abstracts-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/quick-wordclouds-pubmed-abstracts-r/</guid>
      <description>Wordclouds are one of the most visually straightforward, compelling ways of displaying text info in a graph.
Of course, we have a lot of web pages (and even apps) that, given an input text, will plot you some nice tagclouds. However, when you need reproducible results, or getting done complex tasks -like combined wordclouds from several files-, a programming environment may be the best option.
In R, there are (as always), several alternatives to get this done, such as tagcloud and wordcloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R/Shiny for clinical trials: simple randomization tables</title>
      <link>/2016/06/r-shiny-clinical-trials-randomization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/r-shiny-clinical-trials-randomization/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I most like from R + Shiny is that it enables me to serve the power and flexibility of R in small “chunks” to cover different needs, allowing people not used to R to benefit from it. However, what I like most is that’s really fun and easy to program those utilities for a person without any specific programming background.
Here’s a small hack done in R/Shiny: it covered an urgent need for a study involving patient randomisation to two branches of treatment, in what is commonly known as a clinical trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install R in Android, via GNURoot -no root required!</title>
      <link>/2014/09/r-in-android-gnuroot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/r-in-android-gnuroot/</guid>
      <description>Playing with my tablet some time ago, I wondered if installing R could be possible. You know, a small android device “to the power of R”…
After searching on Google from time to time, I came across some interesting possibilities:
 R Instructor, created “to bridge the gap between authoritative (but expensive) reference textbooks and free but often technical and difficult to understand help files”.
 R Console Free. provides the necessary C, C++ and Fortran compilers to build and install R packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>