<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medicine on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medicine on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with post-hoc power with R - why we shouldn’t do it</title>
      <link>/2020/01/playing-with-post-hoc-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/playing-with-post-hoc-power/</guid>
      <description>Current state of the matter The reason for bringing this here is that I witnessed an interesting exchange some time ago, regarding one article and their use of post-hoc power, pinpointed by @ADAlthousePhD:
 Hi @scottlemaire, I would like to issue a public expression of concern about a paper published recently in the Journal of Surgical Research, on which you are the editor in chief.
&amp;mdash; Andrew Althouse (@ADAlthousePhD) April 30, 2019  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biostatisticians… beware of fuzzy researchers!</title>
      <link>/2013/06/biostatisticians-beware-of-fuzzy-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/06/biostatisticians-beware-of-fuzzy-researchers/</guid>
      <description>In the last days I was thinking about about how researchers could collaborate efficiently with their experts in statistics. With the increasing complexity in science, interchanging information can be crucial to get the best results. But what happens when a researcher doesn’t give all the information a statistician needs?.
When someone asks for help in statistics -as a clinician, I need it often-, many biostatisticians ensure that some basic points are met in a research study -prior to their analysis-, and I think they should ask for them as soon as possible:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>