<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with post-hoc power with R - why we shouldn’t do it</title>
      <link>/2020/01/playing-with-post-hoc-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/playing-with-post-hoc-power/</guid>
      <description>Current state of the matter The reason for bringing this here is that I witnessed an interesting exchange some time ago, regarding one article and their use of post-hoc power, pinpointed by @ADAlthousePhD:
 Hi @scottlemaire, I would like to issue a public expression of concern about a paper published recently in the Journal of Surgical Research, on which you are the editor in chief.
&amp;mdash; Andrew Althouse (@ADAlthousePhD) April 30, 2019  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power and sample size calculator for mitochondrial DNA association studies (Shiny)</title>
      <link>/2013/07/power-sample-size-mitochondrial-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/power-sample-size-mitochondrial-dna/</guid>
      <description>The functions detailed inside the piece of code below (in a Gist) has been useful for me when I had to calculate many possible scenarios of statistical power and sample size. The formulae were taken from the article of Samuels et al., AJHG 2006, and the script showed even useful for making a variety of comparative plots.
This is intended for estimating power/ sample size in association studies, involving mitochondrial DNA haplogroups (which are categories whose frequencies depend on each other), on a Chi-square test basis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>