<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Texworks on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/texworks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Texworks on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/texworks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>...learning LaTeX, from scratch!</title>
      <link>/2013/05/learning-latex-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/learning-latex-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>“LaTeX is a high-quality typesetting system; it includes features designed for the production of technical and scientific documentation, and is the de facto standard for the communication and publication of scientific documents.”
 
It is also… Free and Open. Specially designed for beautiful documents even when they include special language: mathematic formulae, phonetic symbols, musical notation…
The mix of normal text with special languages is indeed much better arranged in LaTeX than in any other text editor, so maybe it can be interesting for you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>…start using Sweave, from scratch!</title>
      <link>/2013/05/start-using-sweave-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/start-using-sweave-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION CONFIGURING SWEAVE FOR TEXWORKS In MS Windows In (K)Ubuntu &amp;amp; MacOSX  WRITING A .RNW FILE EDIT FOR TEXWORKS IN UBUNTU FURTHER READINGS   INTRODUCTION Sweave is nothing more, nothing less than one of the best ways R can connect with a text editor, in this case LaTeX.
So you don’t know anyting about LaTeX? neither did I 8 months ago… The hyperlinks in this post will take you to some great pages, to learn different things in an organised way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>