<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ggplot2 on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ggplot2 on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>heatmaps with p-values (2)... coloured according to odds ratio</title>
      <link>/2013/05/heatmaps-p-values-coloured-by-odds-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/heatmaps-p-values-coloured-by-odds-ratio/</guid>
      <description>I like heatplots with p-values -or frequencies, or whatever-. Not very conclusive, but pretty anyway. And when talking about graphs, pretty will make our neurons to fire in more interesting ways: neurons like “pretty” graphs. Moreover, observing your data can be as important as analysing it. It’s better to observe, to listen your patients than making tests without knowing very much about them…
In the heatmaps of the previous post, not a lot of information can be included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>... ridiculously photogenic factors (heatmap with p-values)</title>
      <link>/2013/05/ridiculously-photogenic-heatmap-p-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/ridiculously-photogenic-heatmap-p-values/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago, I had to explore a vast amount of categorical variables before making some multivariate analyses.
One good way to know your raw data, to make new hypotheses…etc, is to calculate some pairwise “crude” chi-square tests of independence of your factors, but it can be very time-consuming.
I mean, not time-consuming to make the tests (with a simple command it can be done), but to revise all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinhart, Rogoff... and R</title>
      <link>/2013/04/reinhart-rogoff-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/04/reinhart-rogoff-and-r/</guid>
      <description>Reinhart, Rogoff… and R EDIT: At the time I wrote this post, I didn’t know of the existence of this great one, from Christopher Gandrud, take a look!
On april, the 15th, an article was published that will change economic theories… Or at least, it will questionate and change the methods employed to formule those theories. As a doctor, I spend time on reviewing evidence that can be applied to daily practice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>