<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Factors on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/factors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Factors on Tales of R - Rmarkdown Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/factors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>...start using R, from scratch!</title>
      <link>/2013/11/using-r-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/using-r-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, since I was able to use R by myself, have found some fellows and other people who wanted to learn R as well. Then I pointed them to help pages, to CRAN repositories… but in some cases they said that didn’t know how to start using those resources. Obviously, the main self-perceived limitation for non-programmers is the use of “commands” -ok, many of the 80’s kids will remember the use of some command lines to access games such as PacMan, Frogger… 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>heatmaps with p-values (2)... coloured according to odds ratio</title>
      <link>/2013/05/heatmaps-p-values-coloured-by-odds-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/heatmaps-p-values-coloured-by-odds-ratio/</guid>
      <description>I like heatplots with p-values -or frequencies, or whatever-. Not very conclusive, but pretty anyway. And when talking about graphs, pretty will make our neurons to fire in more interesting ways: neurons like “pretty” graphs. Moreover, observing your data can be as important as analysing it. It’s better to observe, to listen your patients than making tests without knowing very much about them…
In the heatmaps of the previous post, not a lot of information can be included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>... ridiculously photogenic factors (heatmap with p-values)</title>
      <link>/2013/05/ridiculously-photogenic-heatmap-p-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/ridiculously-photogenic-heatmap-p-values/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago, I had to explore a vast amount of categorical variables before making some multivariate analyses.
One good way to know your raw data, to make new hypotheses…etc, is to calculate some pairwise “crude” chi-square tests of independence of your factors, but it can be very time-consuming.
I mean, not time-consuming to make the tests (with a simple command it can be done), but to revise all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>